# Cecilia Chimento

Seattle, WA | 843-810-9921 | ccchimento@gmail.com LinkedIn | Website | Github | Blog

### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Experienced using technologies such as JavaScript, React, Python, SQL, and Flask. With five years of critical care nursing experience, I am highly adaptable to fast-paced, high-pressure environments and have strong collaboration, communication, and analytical skills. This emphasis on problem-solving and precision is just a small part of my unique blend of healthcare expertise and software development skills that I am eager to contribute to innovative teams.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, Next.js, Python, Flask, SQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, HTML, CSS, Git, GitHub, RESTful APIs, Miro, Figma, Chart.js, Beautiful Soup, Material UI, Semantic UI, Tailwind CSS

#### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School 03/2024

Full Stack Web Development, Software Engineering, Member of Lovelace Fellowship

Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC

Bachelor of Science in Nursing, GPA: 3.95, Summa Cum Laude

05/2018

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# EMpowR - Github | Demo

A platform for users to store healthcare data in one convenient location, empowering users to take control of their health.

- Utilized web technologies such as JavaScript, React and Material UI to deliver an intuitive user experience.
- Integrated Chart.js to provide engaging health metric visualization and insightful data representation.
- Engineered the backend infrastructure with Python, Beautiful Soup, and Flask-SQLAlchemy for robust data management and privacy compliance.
- Incorporated html2canvas and jsPDF for PDF downloads of health metrics reports, allowing users to conveniently share their metrics with their healthcare providers.

# FloraFriends - Github | Demo

A social media inspired platform for plant owners to track the care they have provided for their plants.

- Collaborated effectively with a partner, utilizing Miro for project planning and GitHub for version control.
- Utilized technologies such as Python, Flask-SQLAlchemy, JavaScript, React.js, and Semantic UI to create a seamless user experience starting at the backend.
- Crafted a dynamic Home page that displays a feed of all users' plant cares, which can be filtered by plant or user.
- Conditionally rendered various components to disable users from editing any information not linked to their account.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## East Cooper Medical Center, Mt. Pleasant, SC

Registered Nurse, Neonatal ICU

- Managed care for neonates in a neonatal ICU.
- Led neonatal resuscitation in high-risk and cesarean section deliveries as the primary NRP provider.
- Mentored less experienced staff, fostering their professional development and ensuring high-quality patient care.

Various Companies 11/2020 - 05/2022

Travel Registered Nurse, Intensive Care

- Adapted to different environments in ICUs in Mesa, AZ; Lafayette, CO; El Paso, TX; and a level IV NICU, the highest level of acuity, in Albuquerque, NM.
- Provided expert care to neonates and adults in diverse clinical settings.
- Collaborated with residents, fellows, and diverse healthcare teams to develop comprehensive care plans.

### Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC

11/2019 - 11/2020

06/2023 - 11/2023

Registered Nurse, Neonatal ICU

- Delivered comprehensive nursing care to neonates in a level IV regional referral center.
- Pursued further education in best practice guidelines, staying abreast of the latest advancements in patient care.
- Implemented vigilant monitoring strategies to detect early signs of patient decompensation.